// creating an array and passing the number, questions, options, and answers
let questions = [
    {
        numb: 1,
        question: "Who was the founder of Nanda dynasty?",
        answer: "Mahapadmananda",
        options: [
            "Mahapadmananda",
            "Shisunaga",
            "Dhanananda",
            "Nandivardhan"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 2,
        question: "The Gufkral prehistoric site is located in which state / Union Territory of India?",
        answer: "Jammu & Kashmir",
        options: [
            "Rajasthan",
            "Jammu & Kashmir",
            "Karnataka",
            "Uttarakhand"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 3,
        question: "Who wrote Malvikagnimitra?",
        answer: "Kalidas",
        options: [
            "Kalidas",
            "Tulsidas",
            "Agnimitra",
            "Chanakya"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 4,
        question: "Sudarshan lake repaired second time under the reign of _?",
        answer: "Skandgupta",
        options: [
            "Skandgupta",
            "Kumargupta",
            "Rudradaman",
            "Parnadatta"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 5,
        question: "The ruler of Kushan dynasty, Kanishka was the follower of__?",
        answer: "Mahayanism",
        options: [
            "Jainism",
            "Hinayanism",
            "Hinduism",
            "Mahayanism"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 6,
        question: "Who was the first Indo-Greek king, who became Buddhist?",
        answer: "Menander II",
        options: [
            "Antiochus II",
            "Apollodotus I",
            "Apollodotus II",
            "Menander II"
        ]
    },


    {
        numb: 7,
        question: "Which among the following site has yielded the cultural remains from Neolithic to Harappan era?",
        answer: "Mehrgarh",
        options: [
            "Dholavira",
            "Mohenjo-Daro",
            "Harappa",
            "Mehrgarh"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 8,
        question: "Simuka was an Indian king and the founder of which among the following dynasty?",
        answer: "Satavahana",
        options: [
            "Satavahana",
            "Kadamba",
            "Ganga",
            "Kakatiya"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 9,
        question: "As per Vedic rituals, which among the following is the divine messenger who receives the prayers and conveys them to the heavenly spheres?",
        answer: "Agni",
        options: [
            "Agni",
            "Soma",
            "Varuna",
            "Indra"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 10,
        question: "Which of the following two towns of Indus valley Civilization were located on the bank of Ghagghar River?",
        answer: "Kalibanga and Banwali",
        options: [
            "Harappa & Rojari",
            "Harappa & Mohen jo Dero",
            "Kalibanga and Banwali",
            "All of the above"
        ]
    },
];